<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: money, | Antony Bailey The PartTimeLegend]]></title>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/categories/money/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-24T22:28:55+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Antony Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin Mining Without Your Own Mining Rig or ASIC]]></title>
    <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/2013/04/09/bitcoin-mining-without-your-own-mining-rig-or-asic/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-09T06:16:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/2013/04/09/bitcoin-mining-without-your-own-mining-rig-or-asic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>What is Bitcoin?</h2>

<blockquote><p>Bitcoin is a new kind of money. It's the first decentralized electronic currency not controlled by a single organization or government. It's an open source project, and it is used by more than 100,000 people. All over the world people are trading hundreds of thousands of dollars worth of bitcoin every day with no middle man and no credit card companies. It's a startup currency which has never happened before.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is the first digital currency that is completely distributed. The network is made up of users like yourself so no bank or payment processor is required between you and whoever you're trading with. This decentralization is the basis for Bitcoin's security and freedom.</p>

<p>Email let us send letters for free, anywhere in the world. Skype lets us make phone and video calls for free, anywhere in the world. Now there's bitcoin. Bitcoin lets you send money to anyone online, anywhere in the world for less than a cent per transaction! Bitcoin is a community run system not controlled by any bank or government. There's no wallstreet banker getting rich by standing between you and the people you want to send and receive money from.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is more efficient than all competing currencies. This will drive its adoption in the same way computers were adopted, in that computers made people more efficient in competing in the marketplace. A currency has value by it being widely used. Bitcoin is a startup currency with a deflationary bootstrapping economy. Its use spreads by providing the speculator incentive.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is going to be the biggest opportunity for innovation that the world has seen since the industrial revolution. An idea whose time has come. - <a href="https://www.weusecoins.com/en/questions">We Use Coins</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Now that's out of the way, let's move on.</p>

<h2>Bitcoin Mining</h2>

<p>Back in the early days you could mine Bitcoin on your CPU as a small time operation. They were pretty worthless, so not many people jumped on. Then the value grew and people wanted more and more, so they invested in bigger setups and the power needed to mine grew and grew. Now we have people producing specialised hardward (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application-specific_integrated_circuit">ASIC</a>).</p>

<p>Well I have moved all my mining operations from my home mining rigs over to <a href="http://www.pyramining.com/referral/xz4nk3r2d">Pyramining</a>.</p>

<h3>Why have I done this?</h3>

<p>Because the price tag for mining is just <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x4o-TeMHys0">too damn high</a>! Also Butterfly Labs is a scam and will never deliver!</p>

<h3>How does it work?</h3>

<p>It's pretty simple. You <a href="http://www.pyramining.com/referral/46zmgqdhy">register</a> and enter the address you want them to pay you to. They then give you an address to send Bitcoin to. They use your bitcoin to buy mining equipment and mine on your behalf.</p>

<p>They obviously get to keep the hardware when your time runs out and they can use this to fund themselves. So it's win-win if you ask me. No more stupidly high electricity bills and noise of mining rigs running.</p>

<h5>Disclosure</h5>

<p>Pyramining requires you have a referrer to sign up. They do not allow you to register without one. The links I have included in this post are with my referal link and I will gain a small fee for you signing up.</p>

<p>If you don't believe me, you are welcome to visit <a href="http://www.pyramining.com">Pyramining</a> without the referal link.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
