<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Uncategorized | Antony Bailey The PartTimeLegend]]></title>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/categories/uncategorized/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-24T22:28:55+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Antony Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monetise your blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/monetise-your-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/monetise-your-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>So we all know that hosting isn’t free and if you are adding quality content then people will visit your site. The increased traffic brings increased cost. I have been looking for several ways to increase my earning revenue without having intrusive advertising (though most people just block adds).</p>

<h2>Know Your Enemy</h2>

<p>Most people will block ads, the most common of these is using <a href="https://adblockplus.org/" title="Adblock Plus">Adblock Plus</a>. While this looks for known entries in a series of sources, you can get around this by hosting the ads on your own server as most people will not bother adding custom entries.</p>

<p>You can also create a piece of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript" title="JavaScript">JavaScript</a> that will look for when the div that contains your advertisement is nulled and display a message asking people not to block your ads. This is unlikely to really work. A more extreme approach is to completely block people from accessing your site if they block ads.</p>

<p>Now let’s talk about adding advertisements to your site.</p>

<h2>Google <a href="http://www.google.com/adsense" title="AdSense">Adsense</a></h2>

<p>Adsense is probably the widest used advertisement platform. It is used of most of the sites I have seen showing ads. It will give you great content based ads on your site. Unfortunately there are a few limitations of the scheme.</p>

<p>They do not allow you to click your own ads. Whilst this seems an obvious one, you would be surprised how you can slip a click of the mouse, especially when an add catches your eye.</p>

<p>The click prices can be quite low, this means that if your site doesn’t have a large amount of traffic reaching the $100 minimum can take a while.</p>

<h2>Adf.ly</h2>

<p><a href="http://adf.ly/?id=2366266">Adf.ly</a> is a service I have started using. It means that all those external links that you have on your blog go via their ad service. This means that you can post links without worrying about a loss in revenue. Whilst this can be a little intrusive for your readers, it is the only real way to monetise your external links and that’s why I use it.</p>

<h2>Referral Schemes</h2>

<p>This is the best way to make money from your blog. They are not <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pay_per_click" title="Pay per click">pay per click</a> advertisements, they are actual products and you only get paid when someone buys the product.</p>

<p>While the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clickthrough_rate" title="Clickthrough rate">click through</a> rates will be much lower, the earning potential will be quite significantly higher from these schemes. I myself have signed up with a few over the years and have altered them depending on my need and availability.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>These are my 3 ways of monetising my blog. You could have others, and I would be happy for you to share them with me. If the ads on my site are to your dissatisfaction, please feel free to block them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
