<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: wot | Antony Bailey The PartTimeLegend]]></title>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/categories/wot/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-25T09:27:35+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Antony Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PGP Key Signing Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/2013/04/24/pgp-key-signing-service/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-24T22:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/2013/04/24/pgp-key-signing-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So you've got your PGP Key and you want to get it signed? Excellent. That's how we build this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_of_trust">Web of Trust</a>.</p>

<h2>Why would I want my key signed?</h2>

<p>If you consider your PGP key as your digital identity then you must see the need to have this verified. The more signatures the more you are trusted.</p>

<h2>Will I sign your key?</h2>

<p>Sure will. All I need is for you to contact me to arrange a meeting. I would appreciate it if you also signed my key at the same time.</p>

<h2>What do I need to bring?</h2>

<p>I use a <a href="https://github.com/PartTimeLegend/web-of-trust-verification-forms">verification form</a> that I have released publically. You can either add your details and print it or hand write your details. I normally have a few spare when I meet people so you can always ask if you've not got one.</p>

<p>Just bring two forms of identification. I'll accept most things, but for reference:</p>

<ul>
<li>Passport</li>
<li>Driving Licence</li>
<li>Utility Bill</li>
<li>Bank Statement</li>
<li>Military Id Card</li>
<li>National Id Card</li>
<li>Student Id Card</li>
<li>Birth Certificate</li>
</ul>


<p>I will not accept:</p>

<ul>
<li>Self printed online banking statement</li>
<li>Letter from your grandmother</li>
</ul>


<h2>Do you charge for this service?</h2>

<p>This is a good question. The answer is a difficult one to answer.</p>

<p>I may ask for you to contribute towards travel costs either in full or part. This depends on your location and how I am feeling.</p>

<p>I may also as part of the verification process ask to take a £1 card payment from you. Once verified I will refund this amount to you as I only want to ensure you are able to authorise a payment. I will process this payment at location via mPOS.</p>

<h2>What information do you store?</h2>

<p>I store nothing. I only want to see your identification documents, I don't note any details and my memory isn't good enough to remember them anyway.</p>

<p>I will retain the paper document we complete with our details on. I store these until I get to a computer I can sign your key from. Once signed this document will be shredded, pulped, compressed and then burnt.</p>

<h2>I don't live in your city/country can will you still sign my key?</h2>

<p>I take these on a per request basis. Due to the nature of this, I will have to look carefully at your details and others who have signed your key. I reserve the right to charge for this service as it requires due dilligence on my part. This charge would not exceed £10 or the equivilent in your country and should be made via Bank Transfer to further confirm your identity. This will not result in a signature of absolute trust, you will receive a casual signature as I cannot absolutely gaurantee your identity.</p>

<h2>What keys have you signed and have signed you?</h2>

<p><a href="http://pgp.cs.uu.nl/stats/F2E50027.html">Key Statistics</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
