<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Antony Bailey The PartTimeLegend]]></title>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-24T22:26:42+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Antony Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Human]]></title>
    <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/being-human/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/being-human</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>So we are a few episodes into the latest series and it started a little rough, and now it seems to be amazing!</p>

<p>I was very disappointed to see they had killed of Mitchell, George and Nina! Though Hal kinda just makes this series worth watching. He’s a great character and I’m looking forward to more.</p>

<p>What do we all think so far?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start it all again]]></title>
    <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/start-it-all-again/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/start-it-all-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>It’s been quite some time since I last had a blag. I was wondering why I hadn’t bothered of late and realised the only reason was that my old webhost suspended my account with no reason and wouldn’t respond to my attempts to get in touch with them.</p>

<p>I guess you’re wondering what has changed, well so many things have changed that it’s hard to know where to start.</p>

<p>I recently decided that it was time to move on from my job as a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_developer" title="Software developer">software developer</a> for a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_house" title="Software house">software house</a> in <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=53.407,-2.9915&amp;spn=0.1,0.1&amp;q=53.407,-2.9915" title="Liverpool City Centre">Liverpool City Centre</a>. I decided to see what was out there, and I found a position I thought would be a good fit for myself. Unfortunately it didn’t go according to plan and so I left there after a short while. I am now working for a company in <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=53.4666666667,-2.23333333333&amp;spn=0.1,0.1&amp;q=53.4666666667,-2.23333333333" title="Manchester">Manchester</a>.</p>

<p>It’s been Christmas! I love Christmas it’s my favourite time of the year. I’ve got some awesome presents from my friends and family including Banana Socks off by BFF and a Slow Cooker from my Parents.</p>

<p>I always try to put as much effort into Christmas shopping as I possible can. I aim to get gifts that make the recipient laugh, but also know that I have really thought about  them. This year, I did so much shopping so early on that I totally forgot what I lot of the gifts where, so when people unwrapped their gifts on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christmas" title="Christmas">Christmas day</a>, I was just as excited as them.</p>

<p>Tomorrow it’s back to work, and I am looking forward to it. I’ll talk more about my job in the future, as it’s a huge part of my life. I love my job and the people I work with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
