<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: economics, | Antony Bailey The PartTimeLegend]]></title>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/categories/economics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-25T09:27:35+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Antony Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin Price Crash and Suicides]]></title>
    <link href="http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/2013/04/12/bitcoin-price-crash-and-suicides/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T06:27:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PartTimeLegend.github.com/blog/2013/04/12/bitcoin-price-crash-and-suicides</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I have seen a lot in the last day or so about the bubble popping.</p>

<p>After unceremoniously <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/1c2r87/im_sorry_but_i_can_take_no_more/">rage quitting</a> <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/bitcoin">/r/bitcoin</a> after it became more like <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/circlejerk">/r/circlejerk</a> I was not aware of Today's pointless posts.</p>

<p>I was on IRC and I was told about <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/1c51ck/i_think_this_subreddit_should_seriously_consider/">this post</a> and I had to read twice to see if anyone was actually serious.</p>

<blockquote><h3>I think this subreddit should seriously consider having suicide hotline info posted.</h3>

<p>Im not joking. This is not a troll. We know there have been countless pie in the sky "investors" in BTC over the past couple of days. Shit Ive read more than one comment about how we've got college kids taking STUDENT LOANS to buy bitcoin when it was at 150+. There is no way more than one person wont kill themselves over this. Might as well make the info known to maybe save a life or two.
I know this will get downvoted into oblivion by the bitcoin religious nuts who think this currency will change the world - because they fear it will only make BTC look bad or make it lose value - tough shit.</p></blockquote>

<p>I was amazed to see how many people had invested more money than they could lose into Bitcoin. I have personally not bought a single coin, nor have I sold one. My current holdings are not tiny and not large.</p>

<p>It just shocks me when people see a highly unstable commodity (Is Bitcoin a currency or a commodity?) and they truly believe the price can only go up. Do we forget about every single economic crash is history?</p>

<p>I'm sure we will see a few news articles over the coming days. Let's see how much people have lost.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
